Matheus Cardoso

Full Stack Web and Mobile apps Developer

matheus.mcas@gmail.com

Summary

I'm M.Sc. in Computer Science on automated fuzzy systems based on feature extraction and selection for opinion classification across different domains. I'm skilled full-stack web developer mainly with Python (Django and web2py) and Angular (both major versions), but also I can work with Node(ExpressJS) and MongoDB. Besides, I've been working with hybrid mobile apps development for several years now, using Ionic SDK.

I have these two passions: scientific research and software development. My ultimate goal is put them together: apply science to develop great products.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

August 2017 - January 2018 (6 months)

It's was a continuation of the work made with Z3 Web.

Freelance Web Developer at Z3 Web GmbH

November 2016 - August 2017 (10 months)

I heavily worked with Angular, HTML, CSS and a rigorous focus on pixel perfect design. Also, I developed a search micro service using Nodejs, Expressjs and Mongodb.

Note.: the contract has end in June, but I've continued to work directly with client until the end of August.

Software Developer at MAQHIN Soluções Tecnológicas

March 2015 - November 2016 (1 year 9 months)

I helped the team in every project they need me. No matter what is the job, I'm there to help, such as mobile apps (hybrid and native) and web applications, with Python, PHP and AngularJS, for instance.

More specifically, I worked as mobile apps developer, using Angular and Ionic SDK, but most of the time I worked as web developer using Python (with Django), building enterprise applications and APIs.

Senior Software Developer at Total Informatica

February 2014 - July 2014 (6 months)

I worked as senior developer in the two projects about a POS (Point of Sale) system, developed with Java and GWT, one for general purposes and the other tailored to SAP B1.

Software Engineer at Total Informatica

September 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 6 months)

I worked as software engineer in a new web enterprise solution to the company. It was a Python project using the web2py framework. I've introduced to the company the concepts of TDD, Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery and SaaS (with the proposal of a new product entirely in the cloud).

I also helped the company to replace Scrum by Kanban and to develop the concept of Kanban to be applied in all company's sectors.

IT Project Manager at Total Informatica

November 2010 - September 2012 (1 year 11 months)

I was team manager of the all company's products. The products were a ERP for micro and small companies and two POS (Points of Sale), one for general purpose and the other tailored to SAP B1.

I also proposed and helped the company to implement and use Scrum as methodology of management and development in its software projects.

Internship at Total Informatica

February 2010 - October 2010 (9 months)

I started as trainee in software maintenance sector. I worked in the maintenance of the company's main product using the xHarbour framework.

Student Researcher

January 2007 - June 2010 (3 years 6 months)

Education

Universidade Federal da Bahia

Master's Degree, data mining; opinion classification; fuzzy logic; fuzzy rule-based systems; feature extraction;, 2012 - 2015

Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Computer Engineering, 2005 - 2010

Honors and Awards

Simulação de Tecidos Baseada em Sistema Massa-Mola Utilizando a Arquitetura CUDA. 2009.

Matheus Cardoso

Full Stack Web and Mobile apps Developer

matheus.mcas@gmail.com



Contact Matheus on LinkedIn